ERIC SAI KIT CHEUNG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I've owned and operated a food business in Hawaii & Brooklyn, selfpublished a fiction novel, and am now a Full-stack Developer specializing in React & Redux, JavaScript, and Ruby & Rails.

I love to build aesthetically pleasing projects, find creative solutions to problems, and am an avid food adventurer & cat instagram follower.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT FEBRUARY 2020 – JUNE 2020

React & Redux, JavaScript, Ruby & Rails, SQL and PostgreSQL

SOKA UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA BACHELOR OF ARTS AUGUST 2008 – MAY 2012

Social Behavioral Sciences - 3.8 GPA

CONTACT



Eric.Saikit.Cheung@gmail.com



646.637.1808



https://ericskcheung.com



www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sk-cheung



erock_esquire

EXPERIENCE

HIES INC • FRONT-END DEVELOPER • JULY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

Designed & rebuilt HIES company website using React JS & SASS/SCSS.

- Incorporated PIXI.js to create realistic water effect on hero image.
- **Redesigned** with higher resolution HIES company logo, hero image, and page images using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator.
- **Reorganized** & trimmed original website content for company's brand & services to strictly include vital text. Utilized React Router to preserve page URL addresses.

CURBALERT • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • JUNE 2020

React JS & Redux, Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to post images & details of unwanted items on street onto a public map.

- Engineered codebase synchronizing Geolocation & Google Geocode API to translate latitude/longitude coordinates into addresses. Incorporated Google Directions API by decoding address polylines and accessing response keys to be plotted on map provided by Leaflet API.
- **Collaborated** functionality between AWS S3 Cloud & Rails Active Storage to store user post images on cloud bucket through Rails back-end API.

HANGOUTS • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • MAY 2020

React JS and Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to plan meetups at location calculated to be equal distance between all participants.

• **Architected** a Rails back-end call to YELP Search API to provide restaurant suggestions at user requested coordinates, and returned response data to be visually displayed on map provided by Leaflet API on front-end.

SUPER PETS • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • APRIL 2020

JavaScript and Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web game.

- Implemented battle animations, sound effects, and background music using a combination of JavaScript functions working harmoniously with CSS.
- **Coded** web audio player allowing user to play multiple tracks during battle with pause, play, and skip with JavaScript class utilizing JavaScript's Audio Constructor.

BANZAI PHRESH • OWNER/SOLE PROPRIETOR • APRIL 2016 – JUNE 2018

Owned & operated restaurants at two locations. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business.

- Ala Moana Mall Honolulu, Hl. We averaged 100 customers a day, maintained a 30% profit margin, with 4.5 star reviews on Yelp.
- Smorgasburg Market Brooklyn, NY. We averaged 200 customers a day and maintained a 25% profit margin.

KINGS OF FORTUNE • AUTHOR/WRITER • 2014

Self-published a fiction novel.

• Received 5 stars on San Francisco Book Review, and 4 of 5 stars on Portland Book Review, and featured review on Kirkus magazine.